The greatest story of friendship ever told.
Young Black Stallion is a adventure, drama,
family film directed by Simon Wincer.
When courageous young Neera becomes separated from her family
in the desert, she chances upon a wild colt.
Together they find friendship, trust, and their way back home only
to discover her family is about to lose everything!
Neera, played by Biana Tamimi.
Ben Ishak, played by Richard Romanus.
Aden, played by Patrick Elias.
Rhamon, played by Gérard Rudolf.
Mansoor, played by Ali Al Ameri.
Kadir, played by Andries Rossouw.
The Young Black Stallion is a 2003 American drama
film produced by Walt Disney Pictures.
Directed by Simon Wincer, the film is based on the 1989 novel of the same name by
Black Stallion creator Walter Farley and his son Steven Farley.
Noted for its beautiful scenery and wide-angle shots, the 50-minute film was
shot on-location in the deserts of Namibia and South Africa.
The film stars Biana G.
Tamimi as Neera, a young girl who befriends a young black stallion, and Patrick Elyas as Aden, although his voice was dubbed by Eric Grucza,
who, for his uncredited performance, was nominated in 2004 for a Young Artist Award for Best Performance in a Voice-Over Role.
The film is Disney’s first production made specifically for IMAX theaters, and a prequel to
United Artists/Ford Coppola's award winning 1979 film The Black Stallion.
Originally scheduled for fall 2002, it was postponed until September 2003, before
debuting in select IMAX theaters in the United States on December 25, 2003.
The film explores themes of world war ii, human animal
relationship, horse, northern africa, desert.
The tone is emotional.